Encounters are mysterious! But cases are even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والقضايا تلفّها طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today's title is a bit unusual! Can you solve the mystery in Part 1?!
عنوان اليوم غريبٌ قليلاً! أيمكنكم حلّ اللغز في الجزء الأوّل؟
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Hey, Mitsuhiko.
ميتسوهيكو
Is there really an empty lot nearby
أتوجد أرضٌ فارغة بالقارب يمكننا أن
where we can play baseball?
نلعب فيها كرة القاعدة حقّاً؟
There is!
!أجل
C'mon, you guys. Play soccer once in a while, will ya?
!فلتلعبوا كرة القدم من حينٍ لآخر، كرة القدم
We're here!
!وصلنا
Huh?
ماذا؟
What do you mean?
وصلنا؟
Right here!
!هنا
This is a construction site for an apartment building!
!هذا موقع بناء لبناية شقق
That's right! Except they stopped construction half a month ago!
صحيح! لكنّهم أوقفوا عمليات البناء !قبل نصف شهر
Then we can play baseball in here?!
يمكننا لعب كرة القاعدة هنا إذاً؟
Yes!
!أجل
We can't get in here because it's locked,
لا يمكننا الدخول هنا بما ،أنّ المكان مقفل
but I found another way in yesterday!
!لكنّي وجدت مدخلاً آخر بالأمس
This way!
!من هنا
Geez...
يا إلهي
Here it is!
!ها هو
There's a hole!
!توجد فتحة
Whoa! You broke it, Mitsuhiko-kun?!
!أحطّمتها أنت يا ميتسوهيكو-كن؟
N-No!
!كـ-كلا
A car hit it.
اصطدمت بها سيّارة
See? There's paint from a car on the fence.
انظروا، يوجد طلاءٌ من سيّارة على السياج
A car must've hit it and made this hole.
لا بدّ أنّ السيّارة ارتطمت به فنشأت هذه الفتحة
Alright! Let's check out the inside!
!حسنٌ، لندخل
I'm going in first!
!سأدخل أنا أوّلاً
There's so much space!
!فسيح
C'mon! Pull like you mean it!
!اسحبا بقوّةٍ أكبر
Go on a diet, geez!
!فلتقم بحمية
Alright! This manhole will be the home plate!
حسنٌ، ستكون فتحة الصرف هذه !هي القاعدة الرئيسيّة
I'm batter!
!أنا حامل المضرب
I'm pitcher!
!وأنا الرامي
I'm infielder!
!وأنا لاعبة الميدان الداخليّ
Fine. I'll be outfielder.
فهمت، تريدون منّي أن أكون لاعب الميدان الخارجيّ، صحيح؟
Alright! Let's get started!
!حسناً، لنبدأ
Yeah.
!أجل
Conan-kun! I can't hear you!
!كونان-كن! صوتك منخفض
Yeah!
!أجل
All right!
!حسناً
Here it comes, Genta-kun!
!ها أنا ذا يا غينتا-كن
Bring it on!
!حسناً، تعال
Conan-kun! It's headed your way!
!كونان-كن! إنّها متّجهة نحوك
I'm just a ball-fetcher here...
...سأكون مجرّد جالب كرات هكذا
Still, this is clearly breaking and entering...
مع ذلك، هذا اقتحام ودخول غير شرعيّ بكلّ وضوح
If anyone sees us...
...إذا رآنا أحد
What's that?
ما ذلك؟
Oh, crap! He's watching with binoculars!
!هذا سيّئ! إنّه يراقبنا بمنظار
Whoops!
!أخطأت
It went over the fence...
...تجاوزت السياج
I don't see the ball anywhere.
لا أجد الكرة
Hey, could it have gone over that fence, too?
أيمكن أنّها تجاوزت ذاك السياج أيضاً؟
That is quite possible.
ذلك مُحتمل
Then let's ask the person who lives there to let us get it.
فلنذهب ونطلب من أهل البيت إعطاءنا الكرة إذاً
Good idea. Let's see...
...لنفعل ذلك، حسناً
That seems to be a back entrance, so...
...يبدو أنّ ذلك المدخل الخلفيّ، لذا
I think the front door was facing the main street.
أظنّ المدخل الأمامي كان مقابل الشارع الرئيسيّ
But what if a really stubborn man lives here?
لكن ماذا نفعل لو ظهر رجلٌ متصلّب الرأس؟
I don't know if he's stubborn or not,
،لا أدري إذا كان متصلّب الرأس أم لا
but someone was watching from the upstairs window with binoculars.
لكن كان أحدهم يراقب بمنظار من نافذة الطابق الثاني
Binoculars?
بمنظار؟
Meaning someone is home, right?! Let's give it a shot!
!أي أنّ المنزل ليس فارغاً، صحيح؟ لنذهب ونجرّب
Alright!
!حسناً
It probably flew into this yard.
طارت لهذا الفناء غالباً
It looks like a haunted house.
يبدو كمنزلٍ مسكون
Why would a haunted house be right on a main street?
هل سيكون منزلًا مسكونًا مطلّاً على الشارع الرئيسيّ؟
Hey, Conan-kun.
أخبرني يا كونان-كن
How do you read that?
كيف تقرأ هذا؟
Watanuki Yoshikazu
واتانوكي يوشيكازو
I think he's coming out!
!أظنّه خرج
H-He's all yours, Conan!
!كـ-كونان، أنت لها
Geez. You got a big body, but no guts at all.
يا إلهي، ضخم البنية لكن صغير الجرأة
Excuse me! Our ball landed in your yard! Could we get it?
المعذرة! سقطت كرتنا في فنائك فهلّا أعطيتنا إيّاها؟
Watanuki Yoshikazu (63)
(واتانوكي يوشيكازو (63
Are you students at Teitan Elementary?
أأنتم طلبة في ابتدائيّة تيتان؟
Yes!
أجل
You're not allowed in my yard!
!لن أسمح لكم بدخول فنائي
That means leave!
!ارحلوا
W-Wait, hold on! Without that ball, we can't--
...ا-انتظر قليلاً! لا يمكننا دون الكرة أن
That's what you get for playing baseball there!
هذا ما تنالونه للعبكم !كرة القاعدة في مكانٍ كذاك
If I catch you in there again, I'm contacting your school!
!إذا رأيتكم تدخلون المكان مُجدداً، سأتّصل بمدرستكم
You can't be serious...
...لا يمكن
He wasn't a stubborn man. He was a stubborn old man.
،لم يكن رجلاً مُتصلّب الرأس بل عجوزاً مُتصلّب الرأس
He could at least let us look around the yard!
كان بإمكانه تركنا نبحث في الفناء على الأقل
Darn it! Give my ball back!
!تبّاً! أعد كرتي
There's nothing we can do.
ليس بيدنا شيء
Like he said, we're the ones at fault for going where we shouldn't.
كما قال، إنّها غلطتنا لدخولنا مكاناً لا يصحّ لنا دخوله
Then it's Mitsuhiko's fault!
!إنّها غلطة ميتسوهيكو إذاً
You better pay for that ball!
!فلتدفع ثمن الكرة
Hey! Let's forget about baseball and play video games at Conan's place!
ما رأيكم بأن نترك كرة القاعدة ونلعب ألعاب فيديو في منزل كونان؟
Y-Yes, good idea! We can have some snacks there, too!
فـ-فكرة حسنة! يمكننا تناول !أكلات خفيفة هناك أيضاً
Boxed eel lunches?
علبة غداء أنقليس؟
Yes!
!أجل
Hey! Don't decide things on your own!
!انتظروا! لا تحدّدوا من تلقاء أنفسكم
Alright! Let's go to Conan's place!
!حسناً! لنذهب لمنزل كونان
Yes! Let's!
!أجل، هلمّ بنا
Huh? There's someone there...
ماذا؟ يوجد أحدهم
So, there is. Is he a client?
معكِ حقّ، أهو عميل؟
Hey, Mister.
يا عمّ
He looks mean...
...يا للملامح الحادة
Did you come to the Mori Detective Agency?
هل أتيتَ لأجل وكالة موري للتحرّي؟
Who're you?
من أنت؟
I live here! I'll show you the way!
أعيش هنا، سأرشدك لها
I'm home!
!لقد رجعت
Welcome back!
!مرحباً بعودتك
Oh, hello!
!أهلاً بكم
Hello!
!مرحباً
Not those pests again.
جماعة المزعجين مُجدداً
Mister! You have a visitor!
!يا عمّ! لديك ضيف
Visitor?
زائر؟
My name is Koda. My younger sister went missing a month ago.
اسمي كودا، فُقدت أختي الصغيرة قبل قرابة شهر
Now, now! Please have a seat first!
!حسناً، حسناً! فلتتفضّل بالجلوس أوّلاً
Ran! Make some tea!
!ران، حضّري شاياً
Right!
!حسناً
I'm sorry, but could you guys play outside a little while longer?
آسفة، لكن هلّا لعبتم خارجاً لفترة أطول؟
Bah. We have no luck.
تبّاً، الحظّ ليس معنا
I'm sorry.
آسفة
So, you want me to find a missing person?
تريد منّي البحث عن شخص مفقود إذاً؟
No. My sister was murdered! By a man named Watanuki Yoshikazu!
كلا، قُتلت أختي! بيد رجل !يُدعى واتانوكي يوشيكازو
Watanuki?!
!واتانوكي؟
The Watanuki-san who lives next to the construction site?
أتقصد واتانوكي-سان الذي يعيش بجوار موقع البناء؟
You know him?
أتعرفه؟
Are you kidding? We met him just now!
!بالأحرى، قابلناه قبل قليل
He wouldn't let us get the ball Genta-kun hit into his yard!
لم يسمح لنا بأخذ الكرة التي !أطارها غينتا-كن في فنائه
He said, "You're not allowed in my yard!"
أخبرنا أنّه لن يسمح لنا بدخول الفناء
Just as I thought!
!كما ظننت
He didn't let you in the yard because my sister's body is buried there!
لم يسمح لكم بدخول الفناء لأنّ !جثّة أختي مدفونة هناك
H-Hold on! Please explain everything from the start.
تمهّل! اشرح التفاصيل من البداية رجاءً
Here you are!
تفضّل
I've seen him somewhere before!
رأيتُه في مكانٍ ما قبلاً
But I can't remember where from...
لكنّي لا أذكر أين
My name is Koda Masao.
اسمي كودا ماساو
Koda Masao (29)
(كودا ماساو (29
I have just the one sister,
لديّ أخت واحدة
and I was born in Saku, Nagano Prefecture.
وُولدت في ساكو، محافظة ناغانو
Oh, I know Saku! It has the Cosmos Road, right?
أعرف ساكو! بها طريق القسموس، صحيح؟
Yes. My sister loved cosmos flowers, too.
أجل، كانت أختي تحبّ أزهار القسموس أيضاً
This is my sister, Sanae.
هذه أختي ساناي
Oh! She's very pretty!
يا للآنسة الجميلة
She really is! She looks nothing like her brother!
!بالفعل! لا تشبه أخيها البتّة
Koda Sanae (26)
(كودا ساناي (26
She has white skin, too!
!بشرتها بيضاء أيضاً
You kids!
!أنتم
My sister moved here six years ago to work for Toto Securities.
انتقلت أختي هنا قبل ستّة أعوام للعمل لشركة توتو الأمنيّة
Two years ago, she became head of the Beika branch office.
وقبل عامين، أصبحت رئيسة مكتب فرع بيكا
But on the night of the 8th of last month, she left to go see a client
،لكن ليلة الثامن من الشهر الفائت غادرت الشركة للقاء عميل
and has been missing ever since.
وفُقد أثرها مُذ آنذاك
And this client was Watanuki Yoshikazu-san?
وكان ذاك العميل هو واتانوكي يوشيكازو-سان؟
Yes.
صحيح
I came to town two nights after, on a Sunday,
أتيتُ للمدينة بعد ذلك بليلتين، يوم الأحد
and learned about this at her office the following day.
وعرفتُ عن هذا في شركتها من اليوم التالي
Around what time did she leave the office?
متى غادرت أختك الشركة؟
Around 8:00 pm.
عند الثامنة ليلاً تقريباً
She supposedly said she was going to stop by Watanuki's house
وفقما يبدو، فقد قالت أنّها ستمرّ بمنزل واتانوكي
and then return home.
ثمّ ترجع لبيتها
Why would she visit a client at such an hour?
لمَ تمرّ بمنزل عميل في ذاك الوقت المتأخّر؟
According to the branch manager,
،وفق كلام مدير الفرع
the stock Watanuki had bought had plummeted in value,
فقد انهارت قيمة الأسهم التي اشتراها واتانوكي
and he was pressuring her into compensating him for his losses.
وكان يضغط على أختي لتعويضه عن خسائره
One of those so-called "compensation payments," huh?
أي إحدى حالات مدفوعات التعويض تلك؟
Did you go to see Watanuki-san, then?
أذهبت لمقابلة واتانوكي-سان إذاً؟
Yes. The branch manager and I went on the afternoon of the 11th.
أجل، ذهبتُ مع مدير الفرع ظهيرة الحادي عشر من الشهر
He says my sister never showed up the night of the 8th!
!لكنّه قال أنّ أختي لم تأته ليلة الثامن
But that's a lie! She went to his house that night, but refused to pay!
لكنّها كذبة! فقد ذهبت لمنزله تلك الليلة، ورفضت الدفع
Watanuki snapped, killed her, and buried her in his yard!
!أثار ذلك غضب واتانوكي، فقتلها ودفنها في الفناء
Say, why do you think she was buried in the yard?
أخبرني، لمَ تعتقد أنّها دُفنت في الفناء؟
For two reasons.
لسببين
First, Watanuki doesn't have a driver's license.
الأوّل، لا يملك واتانوكي رخصة قيادة
He couldn't take the body far away without a car.
فلم يكن بإمكانه نقل الجثّة بعيداً دون سيّارة
Second, late that night, at about 2:00 am,
والثاني أنّ موظّف شركة في المنزل المجاور قد سمع
a businessman in the next house overheard a shovel digging.
في وقت متأخّر تلك الليلة عند الثانية صباحاً صوت حفر بمجرفة
Digging?
حفر؟
A man named Mochida-san who lives nearby.
رجل يُدعى موتشيدا-سان يعيش بالقرب
He says that construction was being done on the main street
قال أنّ أعمال البناء كانت قائمة في الشارع الرئيسيّ
that night between midnight and 3:00 am.
تلك الليلة بين منتصف الليل والثالثة صباحاً
Watanuki unquestionably used that sound to dig his hole unnoticed!
استغلّ واتانوكي ضوضاء ذلك !وحفر حفرةً بلا شكّ
I see. So, did you tell the police about this?
فهمت، لمَ لم تخبر الشرطة بهذا إذاً؟
Of course I did!
!أخبرتهم بالطبع
But Mochida-san had been very drunk that night,
،لكن كان موتشيدا-سان ثملاً بشدّة تلك الليلة
so the police said his testimony wasn't credible.
فقالت الشرطة أنّ شهادته ضعيفة
In the end, they only questioned Watanuki on ceremony.
في النهاية، استجوبوا واتانوكي اتّباعاً للإجراءات لا أكثر
He lives alone, and he's almost never left his house since that night.
،يعيش واتانوكي في ذاك المنزل بمفرده ولم يغادره مُذ تلك الليلة تقريباً
But every Saturday morning at around 10:00,
،لكن صباح كلّ سبت عند العاشرة
he leaves for Beika Central Hospital and is gone for two hours.
يغادر لمشفى بيكا المركزيّ، ويغيب لساعتين
So, Mori-san...
...لذا أريد منك يا موري-سان
Tomorrow is Saturday, so I'd like you to come with me to his house
غداً السبت، فهلّا رافقتني لمنزله
and deduce where he buried my sister's body!
واستنتجت أين دفن جثّة أختي؟
I'll dig her up myself, of course!
!سأستخرجها بنفسي بالطبع
In other words, you want me to sneak into his yard with you?
أي أنّك تريد منّي التسلّل لفنائه معك؟
Yes.
أجل
I'm afraid I can't.
لا أستطيع ذلك
It's illegal to enter others' yards without permission.
دخول فناء الآخرين بلا إذن سلوك غير شرعيّ
Besides, skilled as I am, it'd be impossible to tell, in such a short time,
،كما، مهما كنتُ متحرّياً بارعاً فلا يمكنني إيجاد مكان دفن جثّة
where a body was buried over a month ago.
قد دُفنت قبل شهر في ذاك الوقت الوجيز
Koda-san...
...كودا-سان
Very well.
فهمت
Just forget it!
!انسَ الأمر
Koda-san...
...كودا-سان
I'm sorry for bothering you.
أعتذر على إزعاجك
Umm...
...المعذرة
Now I remember!
!تذكّرت
That person looks just like a Mole Alien!
!هذا الشخص يبدو مثل فضائيّ الخلد
Mole?
...فضائيّ
Alien?
الخلد؟
He does, come to think of it!
!معكِ حق، يشبهه بالفعل
They suddenly come out of the ground, just like moles!
!يخرج من الأرض فجأةً مثل الخلد
Oh! So that's why he wanted to dig up the yard!
!فهمت! لذا أراد حفر الفناء
Hey, now. That's not why at all.
...أنتم، ليس الأمر هكذا
Are you just going to let him go, Dad?
أبي، أستتركه هكذا وحسب؟
What am I supposed to do? He told me to forget about it.
ليس بيدي حيلة، فقد أخبرني أن أنسى الموضوع بنفسه
Besides, he's certain this Watanuki killed his sister and buried her,
كما أنّه متيقّن أنّ واتانوكي ذاك ،قد قتل أخته ودفنها في فنائه
but there's no proof at all.
لكن لا دليل على ذلك
Even the shovel sound could've come from the street construction.
يمكن أنّ صوت المجرفة كان من أعمال البناء على الشارع أيضاً
That's true, but...
...ذلك صحيح، لكن
Well, I guess I can give it a quick check.
حسناً، لا أمانع إجراء تفقد سريع بدوري
Yeah, there is some truth to what the old guy says.
بالفعل، هنالك صحّةٌ في كلام العمّ
We can't say anything for sure, at this stage--
...لا يمكننا الجزم بشيءٍ في هذه المرحلة
Alright! It's decided!
!حسناً، حُسم الأمر
Let's do it!
!واحد، اثنان، هيّا
I got a bad feeling about this...
...يراودني شعورٌ سيّئ
How did I know we'd be back here?
قرّروا القدوم هنا بالفعل
First, we need to think of a way to get inside somehow.
بدايةً، علينا التفكير بطريقة كي نستطيع الدخول
We can assume the gate is locked, so...
...يمكننا افتراض أنّ البوابة مقفلة، لذا
Huh?
ماذا؟
It's unlocked.
مفتوحة
Lucky! He must've gone somewhere!
!يا لحظّنا! لا بدّ أنّه غادر لمكانٍ ما
Alright! Now's our chance!
!حسنٌ، الآن فرصتنا
W-Wait, you guys!
!مـ-مهلكم
Yes, there's no way to tell where she's buried just by looking.
لا يمكننا معرفة أين دُفنت بمجرّد النظر
Of course not! We don't even know if she really is buried here!
بالطبع! لا نعرف ما إن !كانت مدفونةً هنا بالأصل
Then let's start digging up the place! I'll go find a shovel!
!لنبدأ بالتنقيب في المكان إذاً !سأبحث عن مجرفة
Wait! Genta!
!انتظر، غينتا
Hey, you!
!أنتم، يا صغار
Beika Police Department
مركز شرطة بيكا
Yes, that Koda fellow gave us a bit of trouble, too.
أجل، أتعبنا ذاك الرجل كودا كثيراً أيضاً
How so?
ما قصدك؟
Watanuki-san lost about 1.5 million yen in the stock market.
فقد واتانوكي-سان قرابة مليون ونصف ينّ في سوق الأسهم
That's a lot of money, but certainly not enough to kill someone over.
ذاك قدرٌ كبير، لكن أيكفي لتقتل شخصاً حقّاً؟
That's true...
...حسناً، معك حق
On top of that, he's certain Watanuki-san is responsible
علاوةً على ذلك، إنّه متأكّد أنّ واتانوكي-سان هو الفاعل
and has been following him around for a month now.
وظلّ يتتبعه لقرابة شهرٍ الآن
The way we see it, Watanuki-san seems more like the victim here.
من منظورنا، واتانوكي-سان هو الأقرب للضحيّة
We're sorry! We just really wanted our ball, so we snuck in...
...آسفون! أردنا إيجاد الكرة بشدّة، فتسلّلنا للداخل
We're really sorry!
!آسفون حقّاً
We're sorry!
!آسفون
It's all right. I was a bit on edge before. I'm sorry I shouted at you.
،لا بأس، كنتُ منفعلاً قليلاً آنذاك أيضاً فأعتذر على الصراخ عليكم
I found your ball earlier.
وجدتُ كرتكم قبل قليل
I'll give it back,
سأرجعها لكم إذا
if you promise never to go to those apartments to play again.
وعدتموني ألّا تقتربوا من بناية الشقق تلك مُجدداً
Yes! We promise!
!حسناً! نعدك
Just a minute.
انتظروا قليلاً
This is great!
!هذا رائع
Yes!
!أجل
One message.
لديك رسالة واحدة
This is Beika Central Hospital.
نحن مشفى بيكا المركزي
You have a checkup scheduled for tomorrow, so be sure to come.
لديك موعد فحص غداً، لذا لا تنسَ القدوم رجاءً
Hey, that sounded like--!
...ألم يكن ذاك صوت
What nonsense! I know that! I don't need to be told!
!ما هذا الهراء؟! أنا أعرف ذلك !لا داعي ليخبروني
Here!
هاكم
Now take it and get out of my sight!
!فلتأخذوها وتغادروا سريعاً
O-Okay...
...حـ-حسناً
He was acting so nice at first, but suddenly grew angry.
ظننتُه يتصرّف بلطف، لكنّه رجع لغضبه مُجدداً
He's one moody old man, that's for sure.
يا له من عجوز مزاجي
Hey! Did you hear that phone call?!
بصرف النظر عن ذلك، ألم تسمعوا ذاك الاتّصال؟
Yeah. It sounded a lot like Koda-san's voice.
أجل، بدا مشابهاً لصوت كودا-سان
Eh? Koda-san?
ماذا؟ كودا-سان؟
You mean that Mole Alien?
فضائيّ الخلد ذاك؟
There's no question about it.
لا شكّ في الأمر
Koda-san plans to dig up the body
ينوي كودا-سان التنقيب عن الجثّة
while Watanuki-san is at the hospital.
بينما ينشغل واتانوكي-سان في المشفى غداً
But, is there really a body buried in this yard?
لكن، أتوجد جثّة مدفونة في هذا الفناء حقّاً؟
Even if there is, it'd be impossible to tell where it is in just two hours.
لو صحّ ذلك، فيستحيل تحديد مكانها في مجرّد ساعتين
What exactly does Koda-san plan to do?!
ما الذي ينوي كودا-سان فعله بالضبط؟
The next day (Saturday)
(اليوم التالي (السبت
Hey! Conan! What time is it?
كونان! ما الساعة الآن؟
Seven minutes to 10:00.
العاشرة إلّا سبع دقائق
Even after I told them not to come...
...بعدما أخبرتهم مراراً بعدم القدوم
That certainly is a big shovel!
جلبت مجرفةً كبيرة بحقّ
I thought I'd help the Mole Alien dig up the body!
فكّرتُ بمساعدة فضائيّ الخلد !في التنقيب عن الجثّة
Say, what do you plan to do, Conan-kun?
أخبرني، ما الذي تنوي فعله يا كونان-كن؟
I intend to stop Koda-san somehow.
أنوي إيقاف كودا-سان بشكلٍ ما
Whatever the reason, sneaking onto others' property isn't right.
مهما كان السبب، لا يصحّ التسلّل لمنازل الآخرين
Mitsuhiko! Follow him!
!ميتسوهيكو! فلتتبع العجوز
If he decides to come back, call us on your Detective League badge!
إذا رجع في منتصف الوقت، فلتعلمنا !عبر شارة فرقة التحرّي
Right! Understood!
!حسناً، فهمت
What's taking the Mole Alien so long?
تأخّر فضائيّ الخلد
Conan, what time is it?
كونان، ما الساعة الآن؟
10:10.
العاشرة وعشر دقائق
That was Inspector Megure!
!كان المفتّش ميغوري
Do you think something happened?!
أوقع أمرٌ ما؟
I'll check it out!
!سأذهب للتفقّد
Hey! Conan!
!انتظر، كونان
Conan-kun...
...كونان-كن
Let's have a look inside, Inspector.
لنلقِ نظرةً في الداخل إذاً يا مفتّش ميغوري
Inspector Megure!
!مفتّش ميغوري
Oh, Mori-kun.
موري-كن؟
Go on ahead.
فلتسبقاني
Yes, sir.
حاضر
I hear there was an armed robbery?
سمعتُ أنّه سطو مسلّح
Yes. It took place about seven minutes ago and...
...أجل، وقع قبل قرابة سبع دقائق
Does this mean you weren't here when it happened?
ما يعني أنّك لم تكن موجوداً أثناءه؟
No, I just happened to be passing by right now.
كلا، صادف أنّي مررت بالمكان للتوّ
Oh, I see!
!هكذا إذاً
I thought for sure you were at the scene of the crime, yet again--
...ظننتُ أنّك في مسرح جريمة أخرى كالعادة
Inspector!
!حضرة المفتّش
The security camera got a look at the robber's face!
!وجدنا وجه السارق على كاميرا المراقبة
Really?!
حقّاً؟
You know him too, Mori-san!
!تعرفه أيضاً يا موري-سان
What?
ماذا؟
Just come inside!
فلندخل بأيّ حال
Inspector! Here he is!
حضرة المفتّش، إنّه هذا الرجل
It's him!
!أعرفه
Just who is he, Mori-kun?
من هو يا موري-كن؟
Koda-san!
!كودا-سان
This man's name is Koda Masao!
!اسم هذا الرجل هو كودا ماساو
But why is he doing a jewel robbery?!
لكن لمَ يسطو على محلّ مجوهرات؟
Whatever the case, Koda ran off with a dozen or so jewels!
أيّاً يكن، سرق كودا مجموعةً !من المجوهرات وهرب
Inspector Megure!
!مفتّش ميغوري
The robber's motorcycle was found near Beika Station!
وجدنا درّاجة السارق !بالقرب من محطّة بيكا
What?!
!ماذا؟
No doubt about it, Inspector.
لا شكّ في الأمر حضرة المفتّش
The plate number matches with the witness' testimony perfectly.
يطابق رقم اللوحة إفادة الشهود
Inspector Megure!
!مفتّش ميغوري
We found this on the station stairs!
!وجدنا هذه على أدراج المحطّة
A jewel...
جوهرة؟
No question about it! He got on the Loop Line from Beika Station!
لا شكّ في الأمر، هرب السارق على !خطّ الحلقة من محطّة بيكا
I want emergency deployment at all stations on the Loop Line!
أرسلوا طلب انتشار عاجل !على محطّات خطّ الحلقة
Understood!
!عُلِم
Everyone else, continue to scour the vicinity!
ليستمرّ الآخرون بتفتيش المنطقة بالجوار
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
Is Ayumi right? Has Koda-san fooled us just like the Mole Aliens?
هل خدعنا كودا-سان بالفعل مثل فضائيّ الخلد كما قالت أيومي والبقيّة؟
Was the whole story about his sister a fabrication?!
أكانت قصّة مقتل أخته مُختلقة؟
But why would he make that up?
لكن لمَ قد يختلقها؟
And, even if he had a reason, why would someone so well-prepared
،كما، حتّى لو كان لديه دافع فلمَ يقدم شخص متحضّر مثله
commit the crime without sunglasses or a mask to conceal himself
على السطو على متجر دون نظّارات شمسية أو قناع لإخفاء وجهه؟
and ditch his getaway vehicle for everyone to see?
كما ترك درّاجته التي هرب بها على مرأى الجميع
A leaf? And it's fresh and green...
...ورقة؟ سقطت لتوّها وخضراء
The fact it's stuck here means someone opened this not so long ago!
كونها عالقة هنا يعني أنّ !أحدهم رفع هذه الفتحة قبل قليل
Wait a minute!
!انتظر
There was one by Watanuki-san's back gate, too!
كانت هناك واحدة عند مدخل !منزل واتانوكي-سان الخلفيّ أيضاً
Could it be?
...أيمكن أنّ
Is Koda-san's true objective...
...دافع كودا-سان الحقيقيّ هو
It's him!
!إنّه هو
He really is a Mole Alien!
!إنّه فضائيّ الخلد حقّاً
Take me to 1st Street in Beika! Hurry!
!خذني لشارع بيكا الأوّل! أسرع رجاءً
R-Right!
!حـ-حاضر
Genta-kun! The old man is taking a taxi back!
غينتا-كن! استقلّ المُسن سيّارة أجرة !وهو عائد لكم
Hey! Mister! Watanuki-san is gonna be back soon!
!يا عمّ! واتانوكي-سان سيرجع قريباً
If my theory is correct, Koda-san is--!
...إذا أصاب تحليلي، فكودا-سان
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Mystery of the Mole Alien (Part 2)."
قضيّة لغز فضائيّ الخلد (الجزء الثاني)
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Manhole.
فتحة مجاري
What kind of holes does Detective Takagi dig?
...في الحلقة القادمة، كبوات الضابط تاكاغي
His own grave!
!يحفرها بنفسه
Nice dig.
!مهلكم